The All New Animated Family Spectacular Adapted From
The Musical By Rodgers And Hammerstein
The King and I is a animation, family, music film directed by Richard Rich.
Widowed Welsh mother Anna Loenowens becomes a governess and English tutor to the
wives and many children of the stubborn King Mongkut of Siam.
Anna and the King have a clash of personalities as she works to teach the royal family about the English language, customs and
etiquette, and rushes to prepare a party for a group of European diplomats who must change their opinions about the King.
Anna Leonowens (voice), played by Miranda Richardson.
The King of Siam (voice), played by Martin Vidnovic.
The Kralahome (voice), played by Ian Richardson.
Master Little (voice), played by Darrell Hammond.
Anna Leonowens (singing voice), played by Christiane Noll.
Louis Leonowens  (voice), played by Adam Wylie.
The King and I is a 1999 American animated
musical film directed by Richard Rich.
It is the only animated feature film produced by Morgan Creek Entertainment.
Loosely based on Richard Rodgers and Oscar Hammerstein II's 1951 stage musical of the same name, it portrays a fictionalized
account of English school teacher Anna Leonowens' historical encounter with king Mongkut of Siam and the royal court.
The voice cast stars Miranda Richardson and Martin Vidnovic as Leonowens and Mongkut,
respectively, with Ian Richardson, Darrell Hammond, and Adam Wylie.
The score, songs, and some of the character names come from the stage musical.
Screenwriters Peter Bakalian, Jacqueline Feather, and David Seidler took creative liberties with the history and
with the source material from the musical in an attempt to make the film palatable to all audiences.
The King and I was released by Warner Bros.
on March 19, 1999, eight months prior to Anna and the King,
a live-action adaptation of the same story.
The film was panned by critics and earned $12 million at the box office against a $25 million budget; its
gross was seen as disappointing compared to that of other animated films released at the time.
The film received five nominations, including the London Critics Circle Film Award for British Actress of the
Year for Richardson and the Golden Reel Award for Best Sound Editing in an Animated Feature.
The film explores themes of forbidden love, musical, based
on play or musical, king, school teacher.
The tone is emotional.